This is a prototype self-driving car that we've been working on.
这是我们创建的一个无人车的原型
We call it Chewbacca.
我们给它起了个名字 Chewbacca
And all around it, we've embedded about 15 different sensors.
在它身上 我们安装了 15 个不同的传感器
Let me show you a few.
我们来看一下
This is a stereo camera.
这是立体照相机
The two cameras together, work just like our eyes to form a stereo image
两个摄像头一起工作 就像人眼一样可以构造出立体图像
that allows us to gather both image data, as well as distance information.
这样我们就可以捕捉图像中的数据和距离信息
This is a camera for the recognition of traffic signals.
这是用于识别交通信号的摄像头
Often, traffic signals can be located on the other side of an intersection, so
通常 交通信号灯都在十字路口的另一边
we use a special lens to give the camera sufficient range
因此 我们需要特殊镜头 让摄像头获得足够的成像距离
to detect the signal from far away.
可以检测远处的信号
This is a radar, and it sits behind the front bumper like so.
这是雷达 它位于前保险杠的后面
Radars have in automobiles for years.
在汽车上安装雷达已经好多年了
You can find them in systems like adaptive cruise control,
在各种系统中都需要雷达 如自适应巡航控制
blind spot warning, collision warning and collision avoidance.
盲点警告、碰撞警告和碰撞预防系统等
Even though radar is a mature technology,
尽管雷达技术已经成熟
it still gets improved all the time to make it even more powerful.
它仍在不断进步 功能也越来越强
While other sensors measure velocity by calculating the difference between
其他传感器测量速度的方法是 计算两次
two readings,
读数之间的差值
radar uses something called the Doppler effect to measure speed directly.
而雷达则通过多普勒效应来直接测量速度
The Doppler effect measures the change in frequency of the radar waves
多普勒效应根据对象是在远离还是在接近你
based on whether the object is moving away from you or toward you.
测量出雷达频率的变化
This is kind of like how a fire engine siren will sound differently
就像消防车警报器一样 当车辆
depending on whether the fire engine is moving away from you or toward you.
正在远离你和驶向你时 听起来声音是不一样的
The Doppler effect is important for
多普勒效应对传感器融合
sensor fusion because it gives us the velocity as an independent measure
至关重要 因为它可以把速度作为独立的测量参数
parameter, and it makes the fusion algorithms converge much faster.
从而提升了融合算法的收敛速度
Radar can also be used for
雷达还可以
localization by generating radar maps of the environment.
生成环境的雷达地图 进而实现定位
Because radar waves bounce off hard surfaces,
因为雷达波在坚硬表面会发生反射
they can provide measurements to objects without direct line of flight.
因此 它可以直接测量对象距离 无需在视线范围内也可以
Radar can see underneath other vehicles,
雷达可以看到其他车辆底部
and spot buildings and objects that would be obscured otherwise.
并发现可能会被阻挡的建筑物和对象
Of all the sensors on the car, radar is the least affected by rain or fog and
在车上的所有传感器中 雷达是最不容易受雨雾影响的
can have a wide field of view, about 150 degrees, or
而且视野宽阔 可达 150 度
a long range, 200 plus meters.
距离可达 200 多米
Compared to lidars and cameras, radars have a low resolution.
与激光雷达和摄像头相比 雷达分辨率较低
Especially in the vertical direction, the resolution is very limited.
尤其是在垂直方向 分辨率非常有限
The lower resolution also means that reflections from static objects can
分辨率低意味着来自静态物体的反射
cause problems.
可能产生问题
For example, manhole covers or a soda can lying on the street
例如 街道上的检修孔盖或汽水罐
can have high radar reflectivity even though they are relatively small.
可能产生很高的雷达反射率 但它们并不大
This is called radar clutter, and
我们将其称为雷达杂波
it's why current automotive radars usually disregard static objects.
因此 当前的车载雷达通常会忽视静态物体
Next up, let me show you a lidar.
接下来 我们一起学习激光雷达